[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
welcome to the stoa everyone i am uh
very excited this morning
uh i'm peter limberg the steward of the
stoa and the still has a place for us to
cohere and dialogue about what matters
most at the nice edge of this very
moment
and today we have zach stein he's
returning to
the stoa as a sense maker in residence
for the month
of september so the the idea of the
sense maker in residence
is um someone who's trying to make sense
of the world
comes in uh for for a month for four
sessions
same day same time um to have some
continuity of thought
uh and then usually the same audience uh
takes along too
um so this is gonna be quite fun we have
dave snowden we have peter wang benita
roy nora bates and a lot of other
daniel gertz a lot of the people being
sensemaker in residence at the stoa
for the next two months and there's
usually an emcee for these sessions
and today's mc who will uh introduce
zach formally and
we'll be uh telling the kind of the
parameters of the q a
is uh what i like to call the most
interesting man at the stoa
nicholas benjamin uh if you're familiar
with nick um
he does the concept unfolding thing in
the past in store which he's going to do
again in the future but nick is an
amazing guy
so i will take a nick and then we'll
begin
today's session
thank you peter welcome everyone to the
stove
so i'm your host nick benjamin for this
sense makers in residence
series with zack stein as a brief
disclaimer i don't condone peter's
epithet of
most interesting men being anywhere near
accurate especially in such illustrious
company as zack stein
and all of you brilliant still goers so
um
zach doesn't need an introduction for
most of you but as a short preamble
he is among other things a philosopher
of education teacher
writer and i would say a polymath
thinker
um exploring diverse fields of inquiry
uh such as the learning in the learning
sciences integral
meta theory justice ethics metaphysics
educational technology religion
and so on um he recently wrote a book
uh called education in a time between
worlds which i've had the pleasure of
reading
opened up my eyes to the potential of
education as the new planetary frontier
and one of his goals is to catalyze
discussion around new forms of education
to bring about a world of educational
abundance and allow for the exploration
of the deeper reaches
of human developmental potential
for the structure of the session it will
be an open q a
i'll i'll start us off with a couple of
questions and
then open the floor if you have any
questions please write them in the chat
preceded by question in in capital so i
can find it
upload the questions that you find most
interesting and mute yourself when i
call on you to ask your question
as you know this session along with all
others is uh recorded
and put on youtube so if you want me to
ask your question on your behalf
please indicate that in the chat so
zach welcome to the stoa once more
um to start us off i i found
chapter three of your book uh the global
crisis of measurements
absolutely fascinating you paint this
picture of measurements and standards
as generating a background justice or
injustice as the case may be
where changing what and and how we
measure changes what and how we see the
world
and measuring intelligence indeed
measuring anything allows for complex
systems
and processes to be reduced to simple
numbers which can often act as
vectors for the marketization of uh
human life towards economic ends
so as an example university graduates as
inputs for the job economy
you yourself are working on redesigning
standardized testing infrastructures
with your non-profit
lactica so my question is might there be
things that we as a society ought not to
measure
in other words a realm of the
unmeasurable we ought not to venture
into
until such time as our individual and
organizational sovereignty reaches a
threshold of responsibility
and integrity should intelligence be off
limits to measurements
and if so how can we even have that
conversation in this hegemonic
neoliberal world
of instrumental reasoning
well that's a hell of a question uh
so but peter was correct that i actually
prepared some stuff specifically on
metapsychology
and had thought about the four
weeks as a continuous experience
educationally
so basically i'm had a song and dance
prepared i'm happy to switch
completely to q a if this is what we
want but my plan for the four sessions
was actually to be lecture heavy in the
first two
and then leave the final two completely
open as question and answer
but i don't have to do that in fact
question and answer is more engaging
often
and that question in particular i'd love
to sink my teeth in
to extemporaneously so
what's our sense okay i'm seeing people
wanting the song and dance
uh okay so people
want to see the lecture okay so this is
what we'll do then this is what we'll do
um because you know i took the
i took the sense maker in residence as a
forcing function of my own
theorizing and work uh because i had
been thinking about these topics of
metapsychology for an extremely long
time
uh and in fact when i first read charles
sanders purse who i'll get into in the
lecture today
and his kind of dp was one of the first
people to have a deep evolutionary
metaphysics
and it was based on this triple of first
and secondness thirdness
as soon as i saw how all of psychology
the so-called field of psychology which
is
vexed as a field is very problematic as
greg hendricks speaks to a lot i'll get
to that
that you could actually start to deal
with the psyche
as such by
working metaphysically first and then
moving into the
various branches of psychology so um
so recently i started first speaking
with daniel thorsen about the topic of
metapsychology
some time ago in the context of
civilizational collapse
and saying listen if there's anything we
need to be able to do
it's to speak to the psyche
in the context of collapse which is to
say how do we manage
the psychological dimensions of
civilizational
collapse existential risk catastrophic
risk things of that nature
and so that was the one of the first
places that i brought the metapsychology
down was in
conversation with daniel thorson and
since then a lot
has unfolded in my thinking so i wanted
to use this as an opportunity to
synthesize a bunch of stuff
and then engage with you guys around
like what's wrong with it
um or what's good about it uh so this is
my
this is my hope so i'm gonna share
screen here
i hate powerpoint presentations but
there are some things that they're good
for so i'm to try to make use of it
in order to kind of front end load a lot
of
thinking about metapsychology and then
that will
serve as a scaffold for a bunch of
questions and stuff
and in the last two sessions that
actually make them more like practicums
where we think about a concrete problem
say in the world or in our lives and we
use the prior theorizing to
to work on it things of that nature
so as i'm lecturing if you have
questions please write them down
and then my sense is before those last
two sessions i'll be kind of gathering
questions through email and
communication
uh and then try to work on those last
two sessions as kind of more
hands-on application kind of stuff so
that's where we'll go
let's see here all right
all right so i think you guys can see
this
so i'm gonna apply these
so this is the place to start this is an
image
uh aeros delivering psyche also
cupid delivering psyche also a more
delivering psyche
so there's a myth in which
psyche is the hero a heroine actually a
female lead character in this myth who
gets entangled with all of these gods
and you know i i start with an image for
a couple reasons
when you're when you're looking at the
life of the mind or
when you're looking at the psyche uh
according to my metapsychology i lay out
three areas symbol image and language
and image is the language
of insolent images the the kind of
way that the deeper layers of the
unconscious
uh and in particular the dynamics of
personality and character
it's conversant in image images have a
certain
setting a certain emotion and context
symbols are universal abstract and
language is
omniscient so the image here is of
basically arrows in psyche
entwined in the revivification of psyche
so there's a dynamic that's pointed to
in the myth
of the impossibility of the isolation of
the psyche from the
all the different dynamisms of the world
system
and in particular uh eros
or love which i write about as a
metaphysical
dynamic that's entwined with the field
of psychology itself
so this is a way of lifting the
conversation immediately out of
psychology of the science and thinking
about
the languages and images and symbols
that the psyche uses to be in
conversation with itself
right
second part of this myth this is psyche
and pan
right so another image setting a mood a
context psyche's so distraught at one
point during the love affair that she
tries to kill herself so she drowned
herself in a stream
the stream will not kill psyche the
stream saves psyche puts her on the
shore
and who's there but pan and pan again
resuscitates so the great god of nature
resuscitates psyche from death
right so love resuscitates the psyche
nature resuscitates the psyche
right so there's a i find both of these
images a little eerie
and a little creepy uh in in the sense
of the
psyche is about to die like psyche is on
the brink
can't take it what are the images
languages symbols
gestures of speech that can be used to
bring the psyche back from
the edge right this is the motivating
point of the metapsychology it's not to
uh
prove in a scientific way necessarily
what's the case with the mind although
that's important
uh it's it's to be able to have
languages that allow
for the
resuscitation resurrection and amnesis
remembrance healing
of the psyche and to do that it means
you have to go
meta on all the various logos of psyche
which means like there's a whole bunch
of work being done under the rubric of
psychology
you know some of it is directly helpful
to that question
some of it is not all of it is
important in the sense of understanding
and sense making
around that question so
metapsychology is i hold it this is my
working
kind of definition which makes it
distinct from some other scientific
metapsychologies
you know the metapsychology is not
trying to resolve debates within
psychology as a field
it's actually not attempting to be a
better scientific understanding of the
mind although
it does lay some claim to be able to
critique science
right so if you if you're critiquing
science then you're
technically not science you're doing
something else right you're doing
something often in the realm
of philosophy um so meta psychology is a
little bit
more like philosophy uh it's actually a
in a habermasian sense it's blending the
three
types of basic validity claims making
scientific ethical and aesthetic
validity claims
this is the attempt with the work
and that's what allows it to be i think
a little bit more evocative
than other approaches to
to the field of psychology
so again i'm saying it you know the goal
here is to
to find and clarify these specific
languages and images
and symbols of the psyche which is to
say their language's image symbol about
the psyche
for the psyche used by the psyche so
it's kind of weird
but this is the way you have to hold it
epistemologically
that there's there's a domain in which
we operate
where we're creating images and symbols
and language about our selves and our
own minds
and our own emotions in our own
relationships
and some of those are
so important for the continuity
and survival of the species that when
you're in a situation like ours of
radical cultural disruption
civilizational decay
you run the risk of losing essential
languages images or symbols that the
psyche has
created to sustain itself right
so one of the reasons to do
metapsychology now and the reason i'm
attracted to it is that the psyche is
actually
root in all its dimensionality the
psyche is root doesn't mean psychology
is the root right it doesn't mean the
things we think psychology is about is
the root but psyche
is actually root to the crisis
and it's these forms of language image
and symbol
and i'll bring some of these to the
front so you can see what i'm talking
about
that are in fact like our most precious
resource
or endangered resource
and this is that notion that nicholas
began with that
human development human potential again
the remembrance and amnesis recovery
healing of the psyche these dynamics of
change
at the level of consciousness uh this is
actually
the frontier that we need to be
concerned about immediately
it includes the sense making ecosystems
the media social media other things
and so metapsychology is trying to
provide some kind of framework that can
be useful across
uh that whole kind of realm
uh so i already mentioned the plan like
i'd like to give some framing
and it'll be loose and it'll be a little
bit abstract
and then i'd like to move in the second
two weeks into application q a
there would totally at the end of this
today they'll definitely be q a because
i'll just probably say some stuff that's
confusing as hell that we need to
clarify before
we move on but my sense is also that
i'd love to take those last two sessions
and make it so that i'd do a little bit
less speaking
and that we have a little bit more
engagement and
people bringing problems to the table
and then we use
some of the frames from the meta
psychology to think about them
so that's my that's my sense of how i'd
like to proceed
so so what i'm going to do now is just
go into a little bit of my thinking
about the history of some of these
topics because i think it's
both intrinsically interesting and
important to
kind of get the idea that
uh you know we've been thinking about
these things for a long time
some of these topics and there have been
certain moves fairly recently
in the history of ideas uh which have
put us where we are today
that there were some paths not taken
especially in the history of psychology
um uh anyway so we'll explore some of
that
so this is actually the place to start
um
at least for me anyway uh
you know so you can begin psychology
early 19th century
but it really picks up speed more
towards the end of the 19th century when
you get the founding
especially in the united states of a
system of journals and
graduate departments in psychology
psychology as a science there was a lot
of metapsychology going on in philosophy
for a very long time but this science of
psychology
uh and incidentally people don't realize
charles sanders purse
who'll figure prominently throughout
this he was actually the first
experimental
psychologist on north american soil
and of course long time best friends
life lifetime friends with uh william
james
who was of course the
the psychologist like the principles of
psychology was
the textbook in those times which put
psychology on the map
so there's a there's an interesting
thing here that i want to get into a
historical incident which actually
reveals some of what is at stake
when you think about metapsychology
so purse was a metaphysician first
and was concerned about basic issues
in what we would now call the philosophy
of mind
and the study of consciousness
james was a medical doctor who had
studied with the german
neurophysiologists
and approached it through a very
experimentalistic
and in some ways empiricist
modality and so james publishes his
famous
principles of psychology 1890 it is
a worldwide sensation and the dominant
textbook in psychology for
decades charleston purse writes a review
and destroys it very fascinating
basically around
precisely this issue of listen there's
more than
one modality of psychology psychology is
not just about
explaining the mind as if it was an
object to be looked at
that there's a whole branch of
psychology that involves
basically first person reflection
of phenomenology and
even deeper than that normativity which
is to say
purse was trying to save
the laws of logic and ethics
from being reduced to causal laws
within the central nervous system so
purse was
saying you can't reduce choice to
causality
and he was saying you can't reduce
entailment which is a normative property
this entails that you can't reduce that
to
causality either and so that was
deep and this is something that i took
from first early on in graduate school
it made me
uh kind of like very concerned with the
directions of
most forms of psychology because what
it's saying is that yes there's a realm
of scientific explanation
where you can look at the psychological
system as a causal system and
make explanations but there's another
equally primordial perspective
on the same phenomenon which is in fact
about the normativity of mine
sapience the presence
both of the awareness and self-awareness
but then also the
norm following rule following
normativity that's part and parcel of
human kind of cognition
so so it's a quite abstract move but
what it shows is that there's a rift
early on in the study of psychology
uh in a sense between those looking for
the broader
metapsychological frame which includes
the reflexivity and normativity
and those seeking to make psychology
more like another
scientific discipline like physics or
something like that
so around the same time james mark
baldwin
uh basically
began the took purse seriously
and basically began the attempt to build
a comprehensive
kind of like fully tripartite
developmental metapsychology so his work
thought in things uh
is like one of these sleeping giants
in terms of like no one's aware of this
work but even people like kohlberg and
piaget
giants in their own right would
basically say well baldwin it was all in
baldwin
so so he took part seriously enough to
realize that you had to take up
different route perspectives on the
psyche as a phenomenon and that you
couldn't seek to
simply have it be a discipline of
explanation
that you also needed to be a discipline
of understanding
and so this this is a root distinction
in the social sciences that was
eventually elaborated but
again explanations about causality uh
prediction uh correlation things of that
nature mechanism
uh understanding is about trafficking
in the norms being used by the
psychological subject which is
basically participating in
the field of agreements and
rules that constitute the life of the
human mind
not as the next not as it can be
explained but as it
as it in its lived experience the the
life world itself
um and so and so this was a very
difficult kind of set of
things to bring together in one
discipline and i think baldwin
you know did an admirable job uh and so
later on i'll look
more deeply into his work um and then
carl jung who
later saw the same
problem from a different angle from a
psycho
analytical angle and of course
you could give whole lectures on jung
you could give whole lectures on any of
the guys i just
went through what i'm doing is moving
through this list of old white guys and
basically saying that there's been a
long discourse
about the the difficulty
of working with the psyche
because you you are psyche
right so the the entwinement of
the consciousness that is
kind of working on itself working on
others like itself
um in lived experience that
and is different from let's say the
laboratory experience
of psychology so
the deepest question then is you know is
psychology like a
scientific discipline or a psychology
like a humanistic
pursuit right and so the guys i listed
here especially jung here
but baldwin also
and people like james hillman and others
more recent in this vein
would say no psychology is fundamentally
humanistic
it's humanistic it's like um it's like
art
like it's intended actually to be
ennobling
healing and uplifting uh almost more so
than it's intended to be technically
true from a scientific perspective
right like there's stuff that jung would
get into he's like i have no idea how to
explain this scientifically
he's like but it happened like the dream
happened right
and there the synchronicity happened uh
and that
one of the components of psychology is
actually to find a way again to
resuscitate psyche to ennoble psyche
um and that the goal is humanistic um
but of course we know that it's not that
there are other people other
theorists and this is the probably
dominant tradition at this point
in the science of psychology see
psychology primarily as a
like another science with the intention
of just saying
things that are true and often things
that
undermined or or contradict common sense
about one's own mind
um this is a fundamental
shift um so like i was saying
uh you know there's lots of ways to
slice it um
so you you can try to locate it
which is part of the explanatory work in
biology culture genetics neuroscience
right so that needs to be accounted for
like i'm not saying this work is not
true
i'm saying that's one basic perspective
on this
massively complex phenomenon
and then you can also dislocate the
psyche so you can locate it in matter
and i'm saying that's a correct way to
go you can also dislocate it
which is also a correct way to go
putting it in the collective unconscious
spirit cosmos or myth right
radically depersonalizing it in a
different way
and of course you can completely
dispense with it
so that means either reducing
fragmenting
or explaining things in such a way that
they
cannot be brought back in conversation
with the life world
so you can turn psychology into
something that alienates the psyche from
itself
if you go strictly towards it being a
scientific
discipline
so basically this is like i recounted a
little bit of my
like existential angst in graduate
school
and when i when i met gray hendricks it
was the same thing where we're like
oh jesus this field of psychology this
science of psychology it's a mess
like most of the deepest questions are
actually philosophical and cannot be
retrieved from the philosophical and
purified and made strictly scientific
like
that these questions remain deep
philosophical questions
including questions in ethics questions
and aesthetics um
and if you get into young and trans
personal psychologists questions in
uh theology cosmology
so you just can't contain psychology
as a scientific field you just can't
contain it
within a simple scientific frame so you
have to
find a way to handle this
rich and the key word for me in this
slide would be
polysemy polysemi it means the same
thing
having multiple meanings right so like a
word
like justice
hell of a word
justice has many meanings depending
who you ask uh so similar
your psyche my psyche the end of a
moondi the psyche collective
when it does something makes an image
makes a symbol
speaks right uh always multiple meanings
you can explain it neurocognitively you
can actually
show how you know it was here in the
brain
that the word came from if you want to
think about that way but you can also
show
the meaning of the word uh what it means
to say it in that
social context what it says about their
psychology their neurosis
right um or you can attach it to an
archetypal pattern
from the collective unconscious so that
the
polysemi the multiplicity of meaning
that is basically intrinsic to the
psyche
and in terms of the way you can approach
the psyche
to understand or explain it so we have a
lot on our hands
uh and the goal is not to actually say
specific forms of psychology like
studying
the way the eyeball works or the way the
neocortex works it's like
that's so important please keep doing
that but at the same time we need people
reflecting on the whole
field again to try to make it so that we
have
language and image and symbol to feed
back into the life world
so that the psyche can stay sane
so that it knows what it's about what's
happening in the world
what it means to be a human those kinds
of things
you know again the existential accident
graduate school when you're
seeing psychology as fragmented as it is
then you realize that basically we run
that risk which i've mentioned
of a rift in intergenerational
transmission where the
multiplying of scientific fields
has created so much fragmentation in the
way the psyche makes sense of itself to
itself if i can say that that the whole
culture starts to go
insane that we don't know what the human
is
we don't know what a person is worth
what people
are what they're capable of who i am the
languages symbols
images that we can use to bring
coherence there
um yeah
become intractably kind of like complex
and confusing
so we need a second simplicity we need
some kind of clarity
on the other side of the complexity of
the multiplying sciences of psychology
so this is the the kind of goal of the
metapsychology
and then of course ken wilbur was one of
the people who basically resolved my
existential angst graduate school
because he was like yup kid that's
correct it is a mess
here are some very large orienting
generalizations
that can allow you to bring some
coherence to this
this is a drawing by alex gray who's an
incredible artist
um talk about image symbol
uh it also includes magistri
who is a bodhisattva from tibetan
buddhism
holding a sword with a book
and so again we have an image here
with symbolism pointing to this deeper
thing which again already mentioned that
you can't
disentangle psychology of the science
from
philosophy you also can't disentangle it
from religion and the thing is typically
classed under
religious concern so it's like if you
are
giving some explanation of human
behavior human motivation
identity construction ethics as a
psychologist
and religion doesn't somehow factor
what have you done what have you
explained religion is one of the main
events
and religiosity which gets into like the
ubiquity of image and symbol
with religious quality even if it's not
quote technically a religion
right this bards like everything's
religion religiosity
is also one of the main events
and so another thing psychology if it
wants to be
serious needs to do is understand that
there was a transition
with modernity in which
psychology began to sit on the pulpit
and psychology began to sit in the
confessional
and that the psychologist began to stand
in for
those members of the social system who
used to be kind of like
stewards of the soul
right and so that is hugely important
in terms of understanding the
responsibility we have
when we speak of the psyche to the
psyche
all right so like evolutionary
psychologists
cognitive neuroscientists like ease up
like what are the languages you are
creating
that people will use to describe
themselves
it's important to think about it's not
that the research is wrong
it's that the way it gets articulated
and the meaning that congeals around it
and how it gets into the cell system is
all part of what it means to be doing
psychology
and so the notion that yes there's a
there's a branch of the sciences
that's related to this broader function
and that broader function is something
like
steward of the soul and it's a rich
educational function um
so all of that with the can wilbur image
so i mentioned orienting generalizations
this is where we're going
i mentioned liberation healing and
amnesis
recovery reconstitution
all of these ways you can frame or try
to put language around
what what the goal is and return to the
original images
right eros saving psyche
right the suicidal psyche resuscitated
by
the god of nature all right like
how can we find the
resources as people
to move through such a complex world
where the psyche
wants to kill itself where the psyche is
despondent
distraught in a literally in a
tragically structured myth
um so
yeah so this is the motivating interest
is to
find those languages that can be used in
those contexts
right the language that pan spoke to
psyche
after the suicide attempt the language
that
arrows spoke to psyche to resuscitate
her from actually looking in
persephone's box persephone queen of the
underworld
gave psyche a box to bring to aphrodite
it's complicated the goddesses are not
nice to one another
and uh she looked at it and almost
killed her
so here's we'll get super abstract
quickly um
so following purse and his critical move
and especially his isolation of an
entailment from causality
and firstness secondness thirdness early
on i started working
every time i was reading psychology with
this meta frame
of which i came to call after reading
landry
transcendence and solvent development so
the basic
these are the the largest categories
which can function together to organize
both the science of psychology and this
other host of concerns that i mentioned
ethics normativity religion
all of that stuff life death um love
sex like anything that the psyche deals
with has to be handled
uh it's gonna fall in one of these
buckets and then it's gonna fall within
certain positions and it allows us to
look at it all
and then in particular to find ways to
to move it back through into the life
world
for the sake of basically education
so i don't know how many metatheorists
are
in the crowd but if you know purse
um or landry or even the wilbarian slash
baldwinian
i we it um then you'll
immediately start to orient to both the
level of the generality of these
categories
and kind of roughly what's in them
and so
kind of simmer on this slide i'm not
going to talk through it
because again this slide is like a
lecture in itself
but i will move to discuss the three
transcendence and someone development
this is the frame of
the metapsychology and it's going to
allow me to
hopefully by the end of this lecture and
the next one
has set a pretty interesting set of kind
of like
languages images and symbols and ways to
work with them
so that we can begin to try to do some
work with the psyche on the psyche
right that kind of work
so i already kind of went through this
um but it's worth
talking here uh in more detail about
you know at the most general level
how can we think about the the different
parts of the psyche um and
you know the one of the classic ways it
was talked about in the medieval
kind of school masters was thinking
willing and feeling and this was taken
up by
uh rudolf steiner
and others and eventually kant um
who put it into you know the
three critiques which end up being
something like truth goodness
beauty um
what we're looking at here is basically
if we take it from the
right and we start with development
cognition right that's the middle one
there
cognition uses language cognition over
time becomes capacity
so the development of the mind is
basically what's usually the field of
developmental psychology
but it's a ton of cognitive science goes
here
it's about how does the nervous system
and the reflective consciousness of the
human
come to be able to work with the world
as
a basically a place where
rules and causality applies so
development is
you know as we'll get into what's
tracked by piaget
it's what's tracked by uh the model of
hierarchical
complexity um elliott jackson's work
and you work on perception any work on
language processing look at it in terms
of this
developmental context
so and i think language cognition and
capacity are actually
transparent as words so my sense is that
when i say language you know what i mean
by language but we could define that
more
cognition as i said is about relating to
the world in terms of object
capacity is about a an ability to
basically operate
consistently at a certain level of
cognitive complexity
so insolent uh deals with a
completely different kind of repertoire
of let's say
psychic phenomenon and psychodynamic
process
um so the main thing analogous to
cognition
but different uh is imagination
uh now you don't get cognition without
imagination
and you don't get either of them without
attention right so it's all related but
if we look at imagination
uh it ends up being a fundamentally
different process
dream being the best example because
everything that is relevant to cognition
which is to say relating with capacity
to the world doesn't exist in dream
because you're not in the world
in the dream you have created entirely
from the faculty of imagination if i can
use that phrase
you've created entirely a different
world an imaginal world
so in the domain of installment you end
up getting all of these things like
psychodynamic projection right where
you're not mad but my imagination sure
makes you look mad
because another process more basic than
cognition
is actually running the show so insolent
is that domain where
imagination is primary image
is the equivalent of language or image
is the very stuff through which meaning
is conveyed
and then personality is the let's say
front-facing or public-facing output of
that
sub-component now they're related and
i'll get to the relations
but you can see like this is different
many of the tools applied
to study development to study language
cognition
building capacity that kind of stuff
those tools don't work if you're trying
to study
processes in the domain of installment
character structure
personality development neurosis dream
imagery that kind of stuff
right like these are just
methodologically they're different
so what do we do to keep them all in
psychology
you have to go up a step so the third
one
is kind of where we start to get the
religious uh
things really impinging upon psychology
this is where you're starting to find
research on
meditation things of that nature uh so
transcendence deals with attention
as the primary so attention imagination
cognition these are
kind of these three images excuse me
three
perspectives let's say on even a single
psychological event
but attention attention has to do with
the self-control of the
psychic system so when you're looking at
meditation research when you're looking
at
research done in union psychology on the
phenomenology of engagement with symbol
and particularly when you're looking at
work in phenomenology
um like uh evan steiner
uh no evan
evan thompson's work that's right evan
thompson's work on
phenomenology of living systems
you're starting to see that uh outside
of language
and outside of image there's a there's a
much different and much
simpler form of
psychological dynamic which i put under
transcendence
it's the one that's most difficult to
speak to almost by definition
uh and it's also the one where you're
getting again
uh religious
symbol and uh language and semantics
like yeah so i'm gonna keep deepening
these but i'm trying to give
an overview so we can continue to
proceed um
and so for you know uh
the best way to you know you can look
across them and you can see
things that are looking similar right uh
and so in development we have stages and
everyone kind of knows about stages
um you know i had ken wilbur on the
screen i've already mentioned psja
and there's a lot to say about how
development works and that's
one of the places i have a lot of
expertise as a psychologist
but despite what some developmentalists
would say
the entire mind which is to say psyche
doesn't only move through stages
parts do and stages are important stages
of capacity in particular
but there are other kind of dynamics
growth sequences evolutionary patterns
which are not best captured at all
in terms of thinking of stages but they
are
uh rhythmic they are often
sequential uh and they are often
transformative but they're not stages
so in installment i call them stations
and we'll look at a couple of these one
of the ones i've spoken about here
in my last visit was pre-tragic
tragic and post-tragic
these being stations of insolent
not stages of development but stations
of insolent so stations is a different
kind of phenomenon
more similar to let's say the
ericssonian
crisis life phases than the piagetian
or the hierarchical complexity models
and then in the domain of transcendence
you get
phases and so these are actually phase
transitions
between different emotional and states
and states of consciousness
right so when you begin meditation and
you're in
everyday consciousness then you have a
phase
shift into some kind of joint attention
or into a peripheral awareness but you
move states you actually in a sense
transcend the state you are in and
realize
a different you know modality of
consciousness
like a distinct also from waking to
dreaming
as an example more subtly you get phase
shifts
from depressive out of depressive or
vice versa but again you have
rhythms and patterns within those phase
shifts in the domain of transcendence
the domain of working with consciousness
to control itself
um which you don't want to model like
stages and you don't want to model them
like stations but you do need to model
them with some kind of
rhythm and some kind of pattern so you
start to talk about
phases basically so
some of this seems like semantics but if
you're working
in a field where people write books like
integral psychology and greg hendricks
books like you need to get the right
setting of kind of conceptual
armature before you move forward so i'm
just trying to lay this out
and a lot of it probably is problematic
and could be refigured
but i'm trying to paint kind of a
general picture here
and so as i mentioned there's a there's
a move between
these which is i think one of the most
important things to get so you've got
development which is this whole area of
skill building building cognition
cognitive capacity becoming smarter
becoming more capable
you've got installment which is this
like area deepening of the personality
enriching the character structure
orienting to death and the deepest
values and things of that nature and
they've got transcendence
which is this ability basically to put
all of that
in front and to work with consciousness
as consciousness and particularly to
regulate
the emotional system uh through the will
and then extracting from image and
extracting from cognition
symbol which moves the personal to the
impersonal
and so there's these three distinct
dynamics
but there's a rhythm to the way that it
unfolds
and this is the one i would propose and
i would propose that
it can run in other directions and then
you start to get
dysfunction and so with this before
beginning to speak to the rhythm
i'll speak to the fact that if there's a
rhythm
and a movement between the triple it
means that there's also
some actual bigger thing that's
happening so i don't know what to call
that
right when all three of these are moving
together right when the installment
process
changes the personality and then that
personality builds more skill
in some area and then that ends up being
looked at
from a transgender perspective in terms
of choice making which then cycles back
into the deepening of the personality
like when this thing is
working then you have what
i don't know what to call it i want to
say like evolution you have the
evolution of the psyche
right but that's a very specific way of
using the term evolution
so you could say it's the the growth of
the psyche
but so we'll see but the point is that
although there are these three
components
and each of them are rich and whole
areas of things and work is done
uh they are related intimately and it's
you need to be almost as concerned about
or am i getting the right rhythm of
their interrelation
um both theoretically and practically
as about how am i doing so called in
each of them
right or what's going on in each of them
so i so i spoke to a little bit but you
can actually boil it down
to again the origins of psychology the
circular reaction
and so the circular reaction is very
similar to what is called in these
circles the ooda loop
all right so this is actually a basic
ooda loop or basic circular reaction
where the uh
personality the installment factor
basically
something like sees a problem builds the
skill
to try to build just kind of like
actualize the image of the person
you build skill uh and then kick it over
to transcendence when you
hold skill and choose basically
you choose and then that creates a new
context in which personality
deepens and so it's a basic thing where
there's a
framing of the problem and attempt to
solve the problem through cognition
of witnessing through choice of
what happened and then on again
so it's basically like saying in
learning theory
um you know if you're trying to get the
child to learn
a math problem or language like
grammar if you don't get the motivation
correct which is to say if you don't set
the personality
in the right image of what they're doing
if you don't get the basically the soul
involved then the skill development is
not going to work
right and in fact this is one of the
biggest barriers
to learning it's not the cognitive
linguistic impairment
um it's often an emotional mismatch
between the task
that the teacher's setting and the like
mood of the child's
psyche the image what's the image of the
situation that they're in
and so you need to set the parameter of
personality
first then move into skill development
and then move into choice which is to
say
what do you do to actualize it
through things that transcend your own
person
basically what's the alter that you
sacrifice self and skill on uh
for what end like with what attention
so so this is the proposed dynamic and
like i said there's probably many other
routes between these three and many
other rhythms
but this one i found to be most
intuitive
so i'm going to keep staying extremely
abstract here
in part because i want to get it out um
so when you're thinking about these
three uh
think about all of them as having
implications with all four quadrants
right
which is to say that installment is a
process that involves
the world and other people and my own
and my own self right and development
similarly development involves the world
and other people
and my own self transcendence likewise
if you're meditating
there's a context there's a tradition
right so
each of these is extremely complex in
and of
itself that personal personality
development in particular
is so radically contingent upon
culture family upbringing socioeconomic
status
like all of that stuff is entwined with
insolent and development but with a
different
kind of slice of causal implication
and then they all shouldn't be thought
of in terms of
symbol essences or structure
that they all have chaos and complexity
dynamics which is to say that if you're
building skill
in the domain of development let's say
and you're in context with a teacher and
you're working on a technical problem
it's possible for you to basically
uh have the context disrupted and lose
the skill entirely
right it's also possible to have the
context improved and they
go up like three notches of
understanding for an hour and then lose
that understanding
right so when i get into speaking about
development there's fluctuations
and uh true kind of complexity dynamics
within just skill acquisition in terms
of model of hierarchical complexity
but there is also similarly in the
kind of like in soulman world that the
personality
is also held in kind of a full quadrant
uh embrace and just as susceptible to
changes in context changes in diet other
things
altering personality rapidly
non-linearly that the personality
will move through various uh yeah
various dynamics um so that's just a
note
necklace you're jumping in yeah yeah i
just want to jump in and say that we're
coming up on the hour mark
oh wow yeah so um i'm wondering if you
have an extra 20 or 30 minutes to devote
to i do
okay amazing too yeah okay so i'd invite
everybody to
start asking their questions in the uh
in the chat
um proceed with with uh questions that i
know that it is
and then um you can answer them so
i i have a i have a question for you to
start things off great
um so you mentioned that language
um image and symbol feed back into the
life world
so that psyche can stay sane
in some sense semiotics aesthetics and
language permit the gelling of these
fluid psychic
experiences into islands of
metastability
signs symbols and words to be
interpreted hills to be climbed
in contrast valley crossing outside of
these systems
through the adjacent possible depends on
a certain ontological
and semiotic flexibility a courage to
break frame and strike out
into the desert and navigate against the
dominant streams of symbolic interpret
interpretation so sometimes language
doesn't cut it
so my question is what is sanity
for you
it was like a long preamble and the
question was like okay what is sanity uh
so it's a difficult question i mean my
first response is actually
like more like foucault like that's my
first response it's
like well sanity is this
thing that civilization creates
it's a category um which has been
shifting socioculturally
for a long time that a lot of the stuff
we do now would be considered completely
insane
to and then what they do is like totally
nuts
so so there's that first notion of like
the word is it's complicated so my first
reaction is
a little bit post-modern a little bit
like sanity is kind of the social
construct
mostly used to get social coherence and
then to oppress
people and stuff like that but if we
take a step back from that and try to
think well
if i'm encountering someone and
i see them in a state of distress
and i'm trying to figure out kind of
like what's the root
of that distress um and then they start
to tell me something
that uh is
let's say completely irrational
like so just in the domain of
development
i'm talking about what you're asking
about is basically what's
non-pathological
human behavior is how i'm re
interpreting the question
so in the domain of development
non-pathological human behavior is
behavior that is accurate true
effective right and so
one of the classic signs of quote
unquote insanity
is people seeing things that are not
there
right classic right like that's a
serious breakdown in the whole
development thing
because you're supposed to be getting
better at dealing with the world through
understanding the world through
cognition and language so if you start
having a cognitive apparatus that starts
to see things that's not there
you know that's a sign of quote unquote
insanity um
so but in the domain of insolent
this is where things are much more
complicated you know
um because the soul
and images of the soul and especially if
you look at those myths
like um the soul basically
is insane if i can put it that way like
the soul is
is pathological um
because it orients almost entirely to
death and a few other dimensions that
make it
such that um you know
if you have your life together in terms
of your skills and capacities and you
even have some good emotional
self-regulation and
a sense of transcendence through like a
religion
uh it's in the domain of installment
this is why psychoanalysis was so
important it's in the domain of
installment
and a personality structure and in the
basic images
that the soul ends up hungering for or
that disturbed the soul
right the images of self and other
um that's where you're going to get the
normal genesis of pathology
and so in those cases what you have to
look at and this i take this from from
hillman
you basically have to look at what is
the archetype
in the pathology such that
it is sane right it's a weird thing to
say
but it's like basically like you have to
find the god
hidden in the pathology that is trying
to be freed
and find a way for it to do that
so and then in transcendence there's
also
pathological behavior a lot of like
religious fundamentalist cults
and that kind of stuff is that would be
pathology of
the transcendent function right where
it's overriding the installment and the
cognition
in interest of basically
exiting so yeah so
roughly speaking i'm not answering your
question but i am saying that
you can find psychological disturbance
across
all three of these and you have to know
what you're looking at in order to help
people who are struggling you know
and you know
in a very basic way our civilization is
insane across all three
vectors unfortunately um
you know there's a there's a simple way
in which from a capacity standpoint
we have a obviously self-terminating
kind of like system of structures of
extraction
and exploitation and from a cultural
standpoint similarly
you know we are deeply
deeply captured by images that
are distracting us out of healthy
behavior
so and transcendence we can get into but
the iconography
and especially the resurgence of um
techno-optimist religious cults like
transhumanism
uh and good old fashion fundamentalist
religion
is the transcendent running roughshod
over the life world um
and what we know about the world so
so yeah so that's kind of a complicated
answer
um your last your last bit about the
um the three domains of metapsychology
that
that um where we're currently
our society can be considered insane
across all three reminded me of the um
the nine planetary boundaries uh
past which beyond whose thresholds we
are uh are slated to to
cause the world to become unstable um
right
so it's more like a metapsychological uh
planetary boundary
i would say
um so so most most of us here are aware
of the magnitude and scope of the medic
crisis
and i get the impression that there's a
race going on between
the exploration of new educational
modality modalities
and the harnessing of tech towards
rethinking the current systems
and upskilling humans on the one hand
and the radical downscaling
of humans in the absolute sense due to
the homogenizing effects of of our
current schooling system
and uh the the forcings of the libidinal
attention economy that we're all subject
to
um and both both forces are gunning for
a certain
hegemony and how do you see this playing
out over the next decade
uh and how do you see insolment as being
implemented
in uh new educational modalities
yeah i mean what to say here
the digital like in like a marshall
mcluhan kind of sense
you know like the printing press and
then the radio and television and then
the digital
the digital is so profoundly
powerful educationally potentially
educationally massively powerful so we
this is one of the themes in my book
it's like we actually
do stand on the brink of something like
a major revolution in education
but it sure as hell not has not happened
yet with the state of the digital
so we've confused the potentialities of
the digital
with what we're calling the internet
right now
which is mostly toxic
advertisement laden uh surveillance
capitalism
mechanism uh and
so that's just one thing to get it's
like you know in the race what is the
race for
uh it's a race basically
for human attention and
the placement of
i think image is where they're actually
going the hardest
like the dynamics of the advertising is
mostly
that and if you look at the major shifts
especially in adolescent mental health
it was both first when facebook got on
the phone
but then more when the scroll
of twitter and facebook was such that
the brief video began to play before you
even pressed it
right so the capture of
soul through fascination with image
i mean this is why you had so long ago
with like the vatican they're like
outlawing images right because the image
is actually the
the most seductive thing that the human
can create is
this image uh there's a bunch of reasons
for that and so
next week i'll talk about in more detail
the difference between image and symbol
and language
and you get to play a little bit with
the notion of what is an image and why
is it so powerful
but most of what we're seeing in social
media and advertisements
on the internet and even now with the
media like news sources
uh is not the equivalent of like a clear
story in the domain of cognition
right it's not like they're laying it
all out to in clear language and
it's not like that uh and it's also not
like they're framing it all in terms of
some universal transcendent
thing that would be weird but it is very
much like it's a
free play of captivating images
and so what that means is that you know
we're confused as hell
cognitively in terms of the domain of
development and we don't know like what
it all means
in terms of the transcendent or how to
even kind of
look at it all and be comfortable with
it all
that's all happening but we're also like
the personality and character structure
and the processes of installment the
capture of that through
intoxication by image that's one of the
main events that's why you're seeing
adolescent
mental health crisis is going rampant
because
it's not from cognitive dissonance about
what really is going on
with those lizard aliens and the
chip in the vaccine like they're not
it's not that it's the
it's literally the kind of hypnotic
kaleidoscopic
kind of like insolent process that
they're that they're in
which is very historically unprecedented
in terms of the forms of image you can
place your identity into
and the ways you can use the imagination
to regulate your
self-esteem um it's uh
so that would be a little bit speaking
into that that space so we have to fight
at the realm of image
and then we also have to figure out how
to show what the digital can actually
do that's not that that that is the
educational power that it has
because that that's basically our only
way forward
um thank you
so uh david sweadlow has a question i'd
love for you to ask it
david
dave you got to unmute yourself we can't
all right all right yes i was uh
obviously there's a lot of interest in
the meta psychotic
meta psychology um this this
conversation
um we were talking about the future
fossils podcast recently
um there are a lot of topics along this
line that that
i'm surprised at how rich this
conversation is and how complex it is
it's a
there's a new recent depth to it um and
it
seems to have uh a lot of consequence to
the possible development of
the ecology of practices that john
verveigh talks about
how do we actually engage in this and
i'm curious if you have insights on
how the collective can coordinate
the exploration of the of the ecology of
practices
rather than just relying on that being
delivered to us actually participate in
the development of the
ecology of practices to help get into
this
does that make sense it does it does i
mean i think
it's very hard to prescribe ways to
start things that need to start
organically
so what i can say is that something like
that somehow needs to start organically
but it's also one of those things that
if you try too hard to start it
then you've just found it a religion and
now you're a sitting duck
so this question of how to basically get
something like this
moving such that if it um
it takes on a life of its own and then
you don't have to answer
or even ask that question right now i
think we're asking the question because
it's
it's hard to imagine something that
would be this profound of a cultural
change not propagating out from some
kind of more centralized
kind of like well-organized thing
so i yeah i certainly don't have any
intention of
trying to to build anything like that
around
my metapsychology my sense is that
because there's so much reflection about
the psyche
for the psyche and that's just saying on
future thinkers like what are we doing
we're trying to make sense of ourselves
in the midst of crisis and so we're
innovating new languages
to help understand our own minds and our
own hearts and souls so enough of that
is going on and then the context is
going to
increasingly create pressure where i
think there's going to be no choice but
for people to get innovative
like that's what's interesting like
before there was psychology
and probably even before there was
philosophy there were people doing
metapsychology
in these contexts right like which is to
say you're with a group of people you
love all these people
just hit the fan how do you say
something to get this group
coherent to stop the people from crying
or to help them cry
right how do we what do we say to do
that to answer that question
you've got to have a pretty complex
model of what people are like
right what are they like what are the
images that capture their attention
what are the practices or rituals we can
do to get to the transcendent
what are the things we can say to help
us understand the situation better
in the developmental so my sense is that
there's a species-specific trait
for this kind of for the psyche by the
psyche to the psyche
language symbol image creation and that
we're going to just start to have to do
that and like my intention is just to
throw a bunch of stuff out there
that people find useful so they can do
it when they need to do it
themselves um and
that's the main goal like influencing
debates in psychology
nope i can do that like it's cost so
much money to get time on an fmri
scanner it's like 30 000
an hour it's like you just can't compete
so you have to find a way to go directly
to
uh you know the quote unquote the people
and try to synthesize the best of what's
out there
to provide enough clarity of framework
so that in a tough situation you can be
like okay is this an issue with
development or is this an issue with
their image of the soul
or is this an issue they just need to
figure out how to transcend this
just framing someone who comes to you
with an issue in terms of those three
because sometimes the best thing to do
is like all right let's breathe just
breathe and
imagine clear open space and just come
like just move the transcendent
and sometimes you'll be like okay we're
going to get the list we're going to do
we're going to do
pros and cons list we're going to do
cognitive behavioral and so we do the
development thing build the capacity to
beat the problem
and then sometimes you need to be like
well what did you dream last night right
like what's the most frightening image
you can tell me about what might happen
all right work in the domain of
installment those three
techniques um those are the three that
i'm pointing to here
which can emerge spontaneously in
practice but with that framing
and then with the stuff i'm going to try
to get into in the coming weeks um more
and more
so that we can innovate because it's we
absolutely have to innovate
because humans have never been in this
situation before
uh it's a mess
thank you david it sounds like we need a
meta psychological bardic
tradition to weave together these
symbols and images
in ways that uh that can begin the
process of healing and
clearing the air um question
by anjen
want to mute yourself anja
thanks nick um hey zach hey
i had kind of a semi question um i
noticed
and then i had a real question i noticed
yet a bit more to your lecture today
um do you have any intention of
finishing that
today or next time next week i'll finish
the lecture
okay even though it's boring and
abstract i know but i just want to get
it on the table
um i asked because i i'm very curious
for the rest of it
um my second question was
how did this framework come to be like
what was the
process of finally starting to write it
down and like
and i'm curious of the story like what
was the first draft and
how did it evolve into the thing you're
showing us
yeah i mean i i told a little bit of it
it started in
graduate school when i was
forced to basically reckon with the
state of psychology
uh and deal with an addiction to reading
charles sanders purse
and basically i have notes
from back then where i start to organize
the stuff i was seeing
from all the different fields of
psychology in these three
buckets which were firstness secondness
and thirdness
in the persian framework and then that
just kind of sat there
and i kind of drilled super down hard
into the development bit
became uh this is you know at the
non-profit leftica
where i um i'm on the board now uh
after being involved operationally for
some time you know just focusing on
hierarchical complexity modeling
developmental learning sequences and
kind of that domain of development
really got that
nailed in um i've been working since my
20s
with various kind of meditation
techniques meditation teachers
kind of an interest in certain forms of
metacognition and kind of like crossed
cross tradition which is to say east and
west
kind of modalities of transcendent so
i'd been
independently kind of working on that
and then the thing that really brought
it
together to allow me to flush it out
fully was a more recent engagement with
the work of
james hellman which kind of crystallized
the insolent vector which before it kind
of be like freud and jung and a few
things kind of like hanging around in
there
um and then it was just there and then
just sat there and i was just
that's what i was thinking in terms of
having read forest landry's imminent
metaphysics
and seeing his triplicate model of basic
metaphysic categories
perfectly interdigitating with the
persian triple
which itself nested with other
metapsychologies
excuse me other meta theories and
metaphysics gave me a lot more
confidence that
there was something quite deep with the
triple and it gave me more
um impetus to kind of really start to
lay out
lay it out so i spoke on thorson's
podcast a couple times
and uh but i haven't written it out
that's why i'm doing this in part
because i'm going to get this
transcribed
and then try to try to basically work it
up into something that could be
a written a written version of it
so yeah but it is in a sense an oral
tradition too
as i'm saying books can be healing but
we need to know
how to speak and what to say and how to
paint an image so that's a little bit
a little bit more of it but i'd like to
in the next year or so get a book out
probably based on these lectures where i
expanded and get the framework much more
clear
thank you auntie now dylan's got a
question
dylan you can unmute yourself now
hi zach thanks for this feels like
you're really onto something i really
appreciate your time
um my question was about
childhood adolescent education in the
context of this
surveillance capitalism economy that
we're in
do you are there any symbols available
today
that are psyche integrating or psyche
healing
within this framework that you're
creating
i mean usually the image
that is healing for the psyche is
created by the psyche who needs it
so like the image work is mostly about
deciphering the imagination and dream
rather than and this is the problem with
our culture rather than
throwing a bunch of images that are not
endogenous to the system
that are exogenous to the system and
confusing the imagination with what is
native to the imagination
right the image that's primordial to the
imagination which is the image that you
can't
help but imagine which is why often it
will
plague you uh it's the it's the
recurring uh imaginal cycles
of personality development so that in
that sense
what you're looking for in the world of
image is a way to recapture what's
native to the imagination
which like the prime mortality of
certain archetypal
imaginations um so in that sense you
want to find a way to
engage young people in
um first of all holidays from
exogenous image saturation
so can we find a way to get free from
the images for
periods of time and then things like
dreamwork
and uh um
joint imaginal exercises uh
that's where you're go hunting for the
symbol that we can't even imagine excuse
me the image right now
that we can't even really construct we
have to find we have to help them find
it this is a lot of what happens in
like jungian psychotherapy and other
forms of psychotherapy you're
helping the person clarify the image of
the self
and that also clarifies right
who am i what's the context scene and
setting
that is kind of recorded the unique self
um and then that allows for
clarity basically so yeah it's not
you know which superhero do you identify
with like
that's not that's what the culture is
sucking us into you know
it's it's like what's the superhero in
you
that's actually keeping putting this one
image in front of your
face so there's a lot more to say about
image but it starts with image that's
the thing
like if you go with a land drain
metaphysics
then the insolent is
primary and the transient tran
transcendent and developmental are
conjugate right which is to say that if
you're starting you start with
with image so you're right to look in
that
direction and uh yeah like that's as an
educator it's
the most worrisome thing is that
overwhelming exogenous just like
way way way too many images thrown at
kids
thank you dylan and thank you zach we're
coming up on time for the q
a i want to tag in peter limberg here
everybody you've been great
and this is a fantastic inaugural
session for the
sensemaker in residence series with zach
very cool thank you uh nick for instant
today and uh thank you
zach for for coming uh do you have any
uh like closing thoughts for us
um maybe what what we should expect for
next time
no i mean i'm just happy to be able to
just kind of do a brain dump on the
stowa and uh so next time i'll finish
the slides we'll move through some other
odds and ends
through deepening into the different
aspects looking longer and image
in particular um but also a lot of
development how to actually look at
cognitive development
how to model that better so yeah i'm
looking forward to that
very cool and i'm happy to um put on the
website for these sessions to be 90
minutes or longer we can do makeup
sessions if we don't get through all the
content uh happy to design it however
uh suits suits you um
so again thank you zach for coming uh
thank you everyone uh for coming
um so here's uh just a few stuff
um upcoming events at the stoa
uh so first if you wanna continue this
conversation right now we have a discord
right there in the the chat
uh you can continue this conversation
one of the chat rooms that they have
there
uh sign up for the mailing list for
upcoming events go to the website to
check it out we have one
today on uh meta modern masculinity with
aaron rodgerson it's going to be a
conversation on
uh modern masculinity that's at 6 00 pm
eastern time
we have a slew of events uh you can
check it out
um if you'd like to support the store
and what we're doing here you can visit
us on
patreon we have about 120 supporters so
far
so if you like what we're doing want
more of things like this please support
us because uh i'd like to give a
tremendous amount of value for free for
everyone here
so that being said thank you and hope to
see you again soon
wow all right